DAMIEN PYLES
1405 Fahlander Dr. North
Columbus, Ohio 43229
Cell: (614) 940-9150
therealdpyles@gmail.com
My portfolio

Resume

Having spent many years in public service, I am currently transitioning to Web Development. My development experience includes Ruby on Rails, PHP, SQL(SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL) HTML5, CSS(SASS, Bootstrap) and JavaScript(JQuery). I also have experience with Git revision control and Unix/Linux commands. During my time in public service, I assisted people with the use of the Web and noted the myriad of troubles they experienced. I am eager to apply that feedback to creating the best Web experiences possible.

Education

January 2013- April 2015 | Web Development, Bachelor of Science 4.0 GPA | Franklin University, Columbus, Ohio

September 2006 - May 2009 | Bachelor of Arts with a major in Political Science | Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio

Experience

8/2010 to present | Customer Service Specialist | Columbus Metropolitan Library: Columbus, Ohio

- Assist library patrons with PCs and library equipment and troubleshoot PCs, copiers and pinters
- · Research and report to management Web resources that can be used for common patron requests
- Devised a process to replace manual checkout for customers in the event of network communication failures
- Manage customer accounts, negotiate fines, manage materials and process payments
- Research and answer patron's reference questions
- Compose and mail letters to library patrons
- Open branch, and reconcile cash drawers

11/2005 to present | Customer Service Associate Columbus Metropolitan Library: Columbus, Ohio

- Shelved library materials
- · Checked in library materials
- Pulled requested materials for library patrons
- Perform general customer service duties
- Maintained library branch appearance
- Assist library patrons with checking out materials

Other Skills

Web Development Pertinent | Graphic Design, Marketing, Project Management

Software Proficiencies | Photoshop, Cygwin, POS systems, Microsoft Office Suite